This is the story of two men who run, not to run, but to prove something to the world.
They will sacrifice anything to achieve their goals... except their honor.
Chariots of Fire is a drama, history film directed by Hugh Hudson.
In the class-obsessed and religiously divided UK of the early 1920s, two
determined young runners train for the 1924 Paris Olympics.
Eric Liddell, a devout Christian born to Scottish missionaries in China, sees running as part
of his worship of God's glory and refuses to train or compete on the Sabbath.
Harold Abrahams overcomes anti-Semitism and class bias, but neglects
his beloved sweetheart in his single-minded quest.
Harold Abrahams, played by Ben Cross.
Eric Liddell, played by Ian Charleson.
Jennie Liddell, played by Cheryl Campbell.
Sybil Gordon, played by Alice Krige.
Lord Andrew Lindsay, played by Nigel Havers.
Sam Mussabini, played by Ian Holm.
Chariots of Fire is a 1981 musical score by Greek electronic composer Vangelis (credited as Vangelis Papathanassiou) for the
British film Chariots of Fire, which won four Academy Awards including Best Picture and Original Music Score.
The album topped the Billboard 200 for 4 weeks.
It reached #2 in Canada, #5 in the UK, #5 in Australia, and #6 in New Zealand.
The opening theme of the film, called "Titles" on the album track listing but widely known as "Chariots of Fire",
was released as a single;  on the Billboard Hot 100 it reached #1 and stayed there for one week.
The film score combines styles from across the musical spectrum
including prog-rock, symphonic classical music and new age.
The film explores themes of underdog, sports,
scotland, missionary, olympic games.
The tone is emotional.